Aurélie Nguyen . Jarvis Consulting

Having graduated from McGill University with a degree in Computer Science, I not only gained an understanding of fundamental concepts such as data structures and algorithms, but also sharpened my time management and problem-solving skills. To apply my knowledge and technical proficiency in real-world scenarios, I pursued two internships during my degree. These internships at Flinks and Intact offered me invaluable experience with the financial sector and its technological applications. At Flinks, I worked with APIs and front-end development, while at Intact, I had the opportunity to explore cutting-edge software like Apache Airflow and Kubernetes. As a competitive powerlifter, I have instilled the importance of consistent hard work and adaptability, qualities that have become integral to my professional life.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Python, C#, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: C, HTML/CSS, Javascript, WordPress, Docker

Familiar: Javascript, Pandas, AWS, Postman, Machine Learning

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/Jarvis-Consulting-Group/jarvis_data_eng-aurelienguyen

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Implemented a Linux monitoring agent to collect hardware specifications and server resource usage of multiple Linux systems. The agent uses Bash scripts to fetch the data, and then stores them into a PostgreSQL database provisioned by Docker. To insure that the information gathered is up-to-date, Crontab is used to run the scripts automatically at a specific interval of time. SQL queries can be used on the data retrieved for analysis.

RDBMS and SQL [GitHub]: Familiarized myself with relational databases, relational database management systems, data modeling, structured query language, and optimizations. Gained practical experience in manipulating data using DBeaver, with clubdata.sql loaded onto a PostgreSQL database deployed in a Docker container. Query results were compared with expected results for accuracy.

Highlighted Projects

excellenceacademique.com: Designed and developed a website for a tutoring company to facilitate the registration of new customers, showcase its services and provide additional information about the company to potential clients using WordPress.

DisposeRight [GitHub]: Implemented a residual neural network using PyTorch and cleaned the data. The Android mobile app written in Java takes a picture of an object and sorts it into one of the four following categories: garbage, recycling, compost, and other with an accuracy of 82%.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (March 2023-present): Worked on multiple projects to enhance my skill set and explore novel technologies in an agile work environment, where I collaborated with senior developers to ensure timely deliverables. My training encompassed various topics, including Bash shell scripting, Linux, Docker, RDBMS and Java.

Vice President, Excellence Académique (May 2020-present): Identify issues and requirements of the company and proposing effective action plans to address them. Manage tutors and clients, overseeing their performance and ensuring their satisfaction, recruit and interview potential employees, and act as a resource person for tutors and customers.

AI Backend Developer Intern, Intact Financial Corporation (Sep 2021-Dec 2021): Improved and implemented new in-house and open source software applications to assist the work of data scientists in the Data Lab. Such softwares include Apache Airflow, Kubernetes,

Software Developer Intern, Flinks (May 2021-Aug 2021): Built connectors that integrate Flinks' API with multiple bank websites, facilitating user authentication and access to banking information. Upgraded the developers' log analytics tool using C#, Typescript, Javascript, HTML and CSS.

Education

McGill University (Aug 2018-Apr 2022), Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science AI4Good Lab (Jun 2020-Jul 2020), 2-month training program, Machine Learning

Miscellaneous

- Powerlifting World Champion 2022Powerlifting Provincial Referee